



andresfch23@gmail.com



313 6272248



Medellin, Colombia



github.com/andresfch23

SKILLS

HTML5 (5 yrs)

CSS (5 yrs)

SASS (5 yrs)

Javascript (5 yrs)

Git (5 yrs)

React (5 yrs)

Jest (3 yrs)

Cypress (2 yrs)

Redux (2 yrs)

LANGUAGES

English (B2 level)















INTERESTS

Pets

Basketball

Movies

Finances

Andres Felipe Chavez Herrera

Frontend Developer

I'm a Frontend Developer with experience in projects that include landing pages and web apps. Passionate about learning web technologies. I have experience working with HTML 5, CSS, SASS, Jquery, React, Redux, Unit testing with Jest, Enzyme and Chai, E2E testing with Cypress and Playwright, and I'm learning another technologies like Node JS, Express, MongoDB and WebSocket.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Austin Software - Howdy / WP Engine

05/2022 - Present

Howdy connects Developers in South America with ambitious US tech companies.

Achievements/Tasks

- Refactor and restructuring of the React app to improve the quality and readability of the code.
- Implemented e2e automated test on Playwright for the Webstack app.
- Fixed several bugs related to the styles.
- Implemented Drag and drop functionality to the rules on the page.

Software Engineer

Austin Software - Howdy / Workrise

08/2021 - 03/2022

Howdy connects Developers in South America with ambitious US tech companies.

Achievements/Tasks

- Fixed several bugs related to the performance and styling of a spreadsheet made with Handsontable.
- Implemented an initial configuration of GraphQL Code Generator to reuse types through the app.
- Implemented a Refactor of code and creation of Reusable React components.
- Implemented e2e automated test on Cypress from scratch.
- Added new automated test cases on Playwright, including functionalities like drag and drop.

UI Developer

Toptal - Oula Health

03/2021 - 07/2021

Oula is a modern maternity center that combines obstetrics and midwifery care to deliver an evidence-based and personalized pregnancy experience.

- Developed wizard forms to get data of the user through different stages of the pregnancy.
- Refactored and optimized a lot of old, low-performance code, replacing it with a readable, clean, and optimized one.
- Creation of Reusable components of React to use through the app.
- Implementation of functionalities that improves the user experience, e.g. search cards with information and highlight text that match with the search text.

INTERESTS

Meditation

Guitar

Web development

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web UI Developer

Globant

06/2018 - 09/2021

Digital agency

Clients

- Intelligence: Fix bugs of the app, change styles and add new functionalities.
- ABC news: Migrate components to React, fix some bugs and develop unit tests.
- DisneyNow: Fix bugs of the app, change styles, and add new functionalities.
- Delta (ABC, Natgeo, FX and FreeForm): Fix bugs, migrate components to React, add new functions and styles to the page.
- Soul: FrontEnd with React and Backend with NodeJs and MongoDb.

Frontend Developer

SolvingBooks

06/2017 - 06/2018

Educative Web platform to students of engineering.

Achievements/Tasks

- Layout of landing pages.
- Develop new characteristics for the user.
- Migrate the proyect to React(create components).

Contact: Jorge Luis Monroy (Solvingbooks CEO and frontend developer) - 3012413046

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Email template (http://email-quality-solutions.surge.sh/) (04/2018 - Present)

- Email template to the company Quality Solutions.
- This project was developed with HTML5 y CSS.
- https://github.com/andresfch23/email-template .

MovieDB (www.pipe-moviesdb.surge.sh) (07/2017 - Present)

- Web app that shows info of different genre of movies like the trailer, description and similar movies.
- This project was developed with HTML5, SASS and jQuery.
- □ The information of the movies was fetched from MovieDB API (www.themoviedb.org).
- https://github.com/andresfch23/Pipe-s-movies .

EDUCATION

Study Program

Udemy

Courses

- The Complete JavaScript Course 2020: Build Real Projects!
- The Complete Node.js Developer Course (3rd Edition)
- React, NodeJS, Express & MongoDB The MERN Fullstack Guide (Recently started)

Medellin, Colombia

Barranquilla/Colombia